[upbeat music]
- Lean left!
向左倾斜！
Now right!
现在向右！
And...finish line!
然后...终点线！
[engine powers down] [beep beep]
[引擎熄火] [哔哔声]
- Good fake run. That was record fake time.
假跑不错。那是创纪录的假时间。
- Yeah! Fake awesome! - Fake awesome!
是的！假得很棒！ - 假得很棒！
- Okay, one of you needs a real mint.
好吧，你们中的一位需要一颗真正的薄荷糖。
Okay, who had a breakfast tuna melt?
好吧，谁吃了早餐金枪鱼三明治？
boys: That was me.
男孩们：是我。
- Well, the bigger problem
好吧，更大的问题
is our lefts still need work.
是我们的左边还需要练习。
In order to maximize speed,
为了达到最高速度，
we need to be totally in sync. - True.
我们需要完全同步。- 确实如此。
- You know if one of you is out of sync,
- 你们知道，如果有人不同步，
I could always jump in.
我可以随时加入。
People do consider me to be the fifth quad.
大家都认为我是第四名成员。
- Who does? - Me.
- 谁认为的？- 我自己。
- Look, it's good to know you have our back, Mae,
- 听着，梅，知道你支持我们很好，
but this year, we are a well-oiled machine.
但今年我们是一台运转良好的机器。
Nothing is gonna stop us from winning.
没有什么能阻止我们赢得比赛。
- How can you be so sure?
- 你怎么能这么肯定？
- Because no one else signed up.
- 因为没有人报名参加。
- [scoffs] Didn't stop you from losing the last three years.
- [嗤之以鼻]这并没有阻止你们过去三年输掉比赛。
Just sayin'!
只是说说而已！
- Well, this year, we're not going to get disqualified
- 好吧，今年我们不会因为迪基不得不摘下头盔而在比赛中途被取消资格。
halfway through the race
- 我只是给了粉丝们他们想要的。
because Dicky had to take off his helmet.
至少我没有像尼基两年前那样一直拉刹车。
- I was just giving the fans what they wanted.
- 我看到一只松鼠，我为小动物刹车。
At least I didn't keep pulling the brake like Nicky did two years ago.
- 那只是一副耳罩。
- I saw a squirrel, and I brake for small animals.
- 我看到一只松鼠，我为小动物刹车。
- It was an earmuff.
- 那是个耳罩。
- Well, it lived.
- 好吧，它活下来了。
At least I didn't miscalculate our entry velocity
- 至少我没有像你三年前那样在欧米伽环道上误算我们的进入速度。
on the omega loop like you did three years ago.
- 我当时才九岁！
- I was nine!
- 好了，够了！
- Okay, that is enough!
- 今年你们谁也不能搞砸。
None of you are screwing up this year.
- 哦，是的，轮到你了。
- Oh, yeah, it's your turn.
- 没人轮到！
- It is no one's turn!
- 我们要夺金，没有什么能阻止我们。
We're going for the gold, and nothing is going to stop us.
我们要争取金牌，没有什么能阻止我们。
[running footsteps]
跑步声
- Except for them.
除了他们。
all: Hello, Harpers.
大家好，哈珀家。
all: Hello, Kramdens!
大家好，克拉姆登家。
[all slurping]
大家吸吮声
- So...you tried to steal our tire commercial,
所以...你们试图偷我们的轮胎广告，
and now you're gonna try to steal our race?
现在又想偷我们的比赛？
- Well, hold on, now.
哦，等等。
We don't know that they're entering
我们并不知道他们是否参加
the Moose Mountain Under 13 Four-Man Bobsled Race.
穆斯山13岁以下四人雪橇赛。
- Oh. We're entering the Mouse Mountain under 13
哦。我们要参加鼠山13岁以下
Four-Man Bobsled Race.
四人雪橇赛。
- Could be a different Moose Mountain Under 13
可能是另一个穆斯山13岁以下
Four-Man Bobsled Race.
四人雪橇赛。
- It's not.
不是。
- We just came by to say...
我们只是顺道来说...
all: Get ready to lose.
大家齐声：准备好输吧。
- Puh-lease!
拜托！
We could beat you in our sleep.
我们闭着眼睛都能赢你们。
- You mean in your dreams.
- 你是说在你们的梦里。
all: Ha ha ha ha!
大家: 哈哈哈哈！
Let's roll.
我们开始吧。
[Kramdens laughing]
[克拉姆登斯笑着]
- Even their snappy comebacks
- 就连他们的机智回击
and mocking laughter are in sync.
和嘲笑的笑声都同步了。
- There is no way we can let those Kramdens win this year.
- 我们绝不能让那些克拉姆登斯今年赢。
- Looks like you kids are gonna have some competition.
- 看来你们这些孩子要遇到对手了。
I just saw the Kramdens dressed for the bobsled race.
我刚看到克拉姆登斯穿着参加雪橇比赛的衣服。
- Could be a different bobsled race.
- 可能是不同的雪橇比赛。
- Well, I know you kids are gonna win.
- 好吧，我知道你们这些孩子会赢的。
Just make sure you keep your helmets on,
只要确保你们一直戴着头盔，
watch that entry velocity,
注意入弯速度，
don't brake for earmuffs and...
不要为了耳罩而刹车，还有...
whatever it is you might do.
无论你们可能会做什么。
- Okay...
- 好的...
racing isn't about winning or losing
比赛不是关于赢或输
or who comes in first or last.
也不是谁先到或最后到。
- That is literally the definition of a race.
- 那实际上就是比赛的定义。
- All I'm saying is it's about having fun.
- 我只是在说，重要的是享受乐趣。
No pressure, no stress.
没有压力，没有压力。
Just get a good night's sleep, get out there,
只是好好睡一觉，出去，
and enjoy yourselves.
然后享受自己。
- Well...that took a lot of the pressure off.
- 嗯...这减轻了很多压力。
- Totally. Dad's usually all about winning.
- 完全同意。爸爸通常只关心赢。
- Yeah. Let's just go out there and have some fun.
- 是的。我们出去玩得开心就好。
- This isn't about fun!
- 这不是关于乐趣的！
[whack]
[撞击声]
- Oh! - Ah!
- 哦！ - 啊！
- This is about winning.
- 这是关于赢的。
This is about our hard work,
这是关于我们的辛勤工作，
and this is about beating those Kramdens.
这是关于打败那些克拉姆登家的人。
[whack] - Oh!
哎哟！
- Who's arguing?!
谁在争论？！
- And it's about getting a good night's sleep
这是为了能好好睡一觉
so we can wake up well-rested at 3:45 a.m.
这样我们才能在凌晨3点45分精神饱满地醒来。
- 3:45?
凌晨3点45分？
[whack]
哎哟！
- I know it seems early,
我知道这看起来很早，
but it is a long drive up that mountain.
但那座山的路程很长。
[boys moan]
[男孩们呻吟]
- Well, if one of you is too sleepy
- 好吧，如果你们中有谁太困了
and you need a backup,
需要一个替补，
the fifth quad is always ready.
第五小队总是随时待命。
- It's not that easy, Mae.
- 没那么简单，梅。
You need a uniform and a helm--
你需要制服和头盔——
[Velcro rips]
[魔术贴撕开声]
- Like I said, fifth quad is always ready.
- 就像我说的，第五小队总是准备好了。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [whistling]
[吹口哨]
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪ ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- ♪ La la la la la la la la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 啦啦啦-啦 ♪
- Gentlemen, we have seen the enemy,
先生们，我们已经看到了敌人，
and they are adorable.
他们非常可爱。
But despite the fact that you just wanna
但尽管你们可能只想
[silly voice] pinch their cute little cheeks,
用傻气的声音捏他们那可爱的小脸颊，
we must keep our resolve.
我们必须保持决心。
Tonight, we sleep as contenders.
今晚，我们作为竞争者入眠。
Tomorrow...as champions.
明天…作为冠军。
- If we don't mess up again. - I was getting to that.
- 只要我们不再犯错。- 我正要说这个呢。
- And if we get a good night's rest.
- 还有，如果我们能睡个好觉。
- Just once, I would like to make
- 就这一次，我希望能在睡前鼓劲时，不被打断！
a bedtime rallying speech without being corrected!
听着，如果我们现在就睡，
Look, if we fall asleep right now,
我们将会获得…整整7小时45分钟的高质量睡眠，
we will get...7 hours and 45 minutes of solid shuteye,
这将引领我们走向胜利。
which will lead us to victory.
晚安，孩子们。- 晚安。
Good night, boys. - Good night.
- 晚安。
- Good night.
你在干什么？- 我只是在确认我的闹钟是否设定好了。
- What are you doing?
- 你在干什么？
- I'm just double-checking my alarm to make sure it's set.
- 我只是再检查一遍我的闹钟，确保它已经设定好了。
I have to hear the click-click to be sure.
我得听到那个咔嗒声才能确定。
[click, click]
[咔嗒，咔嗒]
Sure.
确定。
Not sure.
不确定。
[click, click]
[咔嗒，咔嗒]
I'm sure.
我确定。
Not sure-- - Nicky!
不确定-- - 尼基！
- I'm sorry. It--I'm sure.
- 对不起。我--我确定。
- Okay.
好的。
- Dawn, are you going to leave that there?
Dawn，你打算把那个留在那里吗？
- No. It helps me fall asleep.
不，它帮助我入睡。
I'll put it down once I finish my stretching.
我做完拉伸后会放下来的。
- No, not that.
不，不是那个。
That.
那个。
You know I like things how I like things,
你知道我喜欢东西按我喜欢的方式摆放，
and this thing... I don't like it.
而这个东西...我不喜欢。
- Oh. Sorry.
哦，对不起。
I forgot you like a neat bed. Here.
我忘了你喜欢整洁的床铺。给你。
There. Good night!
好了，晚安！
Mae, why aren't you getting in the bed?
Mae，你为什么不上床？
- Because my mind won't let my body move.
因为我的脑子不让我的身体动。
- [sighs] Fine.
好吧。
- I'll get the drawer for you. - I don't know, it's kinda--
我去给你拿抽屉。
- Aah!
我不知道，有点——
- Thank you!
啊！
Perfect.
谢谢你！
We have a race to sleep for.
完美。
- Oh...okay.
我们有个比赛要睡。
- Why is it so hard to fall asleep
- 为什么入睡这么难
when that's what you're trying to do?
当你正努力这样做的时候？
- [sighs] Well, for starters,
- [叹气] 首先，
you turned the light on!
你把灯打开了！
- I was just making sure you could hear me.
- 我只是想确保你能听到我说话。
- Hey, Chatman and Robin,
- 嘿，Chatman和Robin，
if we wanna beat the Kramdens, we need to be well-rested.
如果我们想打败Kramdens，我们需要好好休息。
- You're the one saying the most words,
- 你是最多话的那个，
so you're the Chatman.
所以你是Chatman。
- Or the Robin-- - Robin's losing it!
- 或者是Robin-- - Robin要崩溃了！
- Sleeve, sleeve, fold, press.
袖子，袖子，折叠，压平。
Mae's the one who folds the best.
梅是最会折叠的。
You gotta stretch. I gotta fold.
你得伸展。我得折叠。
- Ah! Mommy likey early bedtime.
啊！妈妈喜欢早睡。
- Well, Daddy hatey early rise time.
好吧，爸爸讨厌早起。
So I gotta get some sleep.
所以我得睡一会儿。
There's a lotta pressure on this race tomorrow.
明天的比赛压力很大。
- I thought you told the kids no pressure.
我以为你告诉孩子们没有压力。
- I was using reverse psychology to keep the pressure off.
我是在用逆向心理来减轻压力。
- Okay, Tom, I don't think you understand
好吧，汤姆，我觉得你不明白
what reverse psychology means.
你似乎不太明白什么是逆向心理。
The reverse of no pressure is actually pressure.
没有压力的反面实际上就是施加压力。
- Trust me, Anne,
相信我，安妮，
I think I know a thing or two about reserve psychology.
关于逆向心理，我自认为还是懂一些的。
- Anybody else stressed out that Dad said no pressure?
有人因为爸爸说没有压力而感到紧张吗？
- I'm freakin' out!
我都快疯了！
- You know, Anne, if I hadn't gone into sporting goods...
你知道吗，安妮，如果我没有进入体育用品行业...
[exhales] I woulda gone into brains.
[叹气] 我可能会去研究心理学。
- Dad's totally in my brain!
爸爸完全占据了我的心理！
- Let me, uh, give you a little taste
让我，呃，给你稍微展示一下
of reverse psychology.
反向心理学的应用。
Take as much blanket as you want.
想要多少毯子就拿多少。
[chuckles]
[轻笑]
Now, don't give any blanket back.
现在，别还回任何毯子。
Anne?
安妮？
- [snoring]
- [打呼噜]
- I'm not cold.
- 我不冷。
- 6 hours, 47 minutes
- 6小时47分钟
if we fall asleep right now!
如果我们现在就睡着！
- At least Dawn and Mae are sleeping.
- 至少 Dawn 和 Mae 在睡觉。
- Sleeve, sleeve, fold, press.
袖子，袖子，折叠，压平。
- Dawn ain't gonna get no rest.
Dawn肯定没法好好休息了。
- [shivering]
[颤抖声]
[whispers] So...cold.
[低语] 好...冷。
- Your clock is fine!
你的闹钟没问题！
- [clicking] I just need to hear the click-click.
[咔嗒声] 我只是需要听到那咔嗒声。
- Uh, 6 hours, 46 minutes!
呃，6小时46分钟！
- This race is so much pressure!
这场比赛压力好大！
I wonder if the Kramdens are feeling it?
不知道Kramdens他们是不是也感觉到了？
[snoring in sync]
[同步打鼾声]
all: I've got to get some sleep.
大家：我得睡会儿觉。
[upbeat music]
（欢快的音乐）
- If we fall asleep right now,
如果我们现在就睡，
we'll get 4 hours and 45 minutes of sleep,
我们能睡4小时45分钟，
which comes out to--
这相当于——
- 17,100 seconds.
17,100秒。
- Yes...actually.
是的...实际上。
How did you do that?
你怎么算出来的？
- I don't know! But I'm on a roll.
我不知道！但我现在状态很好。
Ask me another question. - What's 5 plus 5?
再问我一个问题。——5加5等于多少？
- 55! - The roll is over.
- 55! - 运气到头了。
- Eew! Dawn, what's that?
- 咦！Dawn，那是什么？
- My foot.
- 我的脚。
You were folding laundry so long,
你叠衣服叠那么久，
I have to do my relaxation stretch again.
我得再做一次放松拉伸。
- If you're nervous...
- 如果你紧张的话...
the fifth quad is here to fill in for you.
第五个四分卫在这里替你上场。
- I got this, Mae.
- 我能搞定，Mae。
- Well, if we're gonna get some sleep,
- 好吧，如果我们想睡一会儿，
I'm gonna have to put my foot down.
我得坚决一点。
Put your foot down!
把脚放下！
- This is way better than a blanket.
- 这比毯子好多了。
Who's the reverse psychologist now?
现在谁是反向心理学家？
- [snoring]
- [打呼噜]
[ziiii--]
[嘶嘶--]
- Stupid blanket!
- 愚蠢的毯子！
Oh...she looks like such an angel
哦...她睡觉时看起来像个天使。
when she's sleeping.
哇！
Whoa!
强得离谱的天使！
Freakishly strong angel!
哇！
Whoa! [thud]
哇！[砰]
Uhh!
呃！
[groans]
[呻吟]
Owwwwww!
哎哟！
[cranking]
[嘎吱声]
- What is that?
- 那是什么？
- It's my backup clock.
- 是我的备用闹钟。
- Why do you need a backup clock?
- 你为什么需要一个备用闹钟？
- In case there's a power outage.
- 以防停电。
- Well, right now, we're having a sleep outage,
- 好吧，现在我们正经历睡眠不足，
and if we don't get some sleep,
如果我们不睡一会儿，
we'll never win the race.
我们永远赢不了比赛。
- Well, if we don't wake up on time,
- 如果我们不能及时醒来，
then we'll never make it to the race!
那我们就永远赶不上比赛！
So if you don't mind, I need to wind!
所以如果你不介意，我需要上发条！
[cranking] Wind, wind, wind, wind.
[上发条声] 上发条，上发条，上发条，上发条。
Wind.
上发条。
There. Done.
好了。完成了。
- Finally!
- 终于！
[cranking] - Wind, wind, wind, wind.
[上发条声] - 上发条，上发条，上发条，上发条。
Wind.
风。
- I thought you said you were done!
我以为你说你已经弄好了！
- This is my backup backup clock.
这是我备用的备用时钟。
- Get out! - No, seriously.
别开玩笑了！
I actually have a backup backup clock.
不，说真的。
- No, seriously...
我真的有一个备用的备用时钟。
Ricky: Get out! Dicky: Get out!
不，说真的...
- You guys asleep?
瑞奇：别开玩笑了！迪基：别开玩笑了！
[door thuds closed]
你们睡着了吗？
- Don't you knock?
你不会敲门吗？
- Well, no, in case you were asleep.
好吧，不，以防你睡着了。
I need to crash here.
我需要在这里过夜。
- Whatever. Just be quiet about it.
随便。只要保持安静。
- Don't worry about me.
别担心我。
I'm no Chatman.
我不是查特曼。
- Who?
谁？
- It's a boys' room thing. Ricky is Robin.
这是男生宿舍的事。Ricky是Robin。
- What goes on in there? - Everybody go to sleep!
那里发生了什么？ - 大家都去睡觉！
- Won't hear another peep outta me.
不会再听到我出声了。
No more peeps.
不再出声了。
I am done peeping.
我不再偷看了。
Sorry, just one more peep.
抱歉，再偷看一次。
- [groans] Ugh! Again with that tuna melt!
呃！又是那个金枪鱼三明治！
- Where can I plug in my clock?
我的闹钟插哪儿？
- You don't need a clock. I have a clock.
你不需要闹钟。我有闹钟。
- Yeah, but I need the click-click of my clock.
是，但我要我的闹钟的咔嗒声。
- What about your other two clocks?
那你的另外两个闹钟呢？
- They don't click-click.
它们不会咔嗒响。
- Then what do they do?
那它们做什么？
- They ticktock.
它们滴答响。
They're ticktock clocks.
它们是滴答钟。
They're not click-click clocks!
它们不是咔嗒钟！
- Now you're just sounding cuckoo!
你现在听起来就像个布谷鸟！
- Oh, yeah, you're right. I forgot my cuckoo clock.
哦，对，你说得对。我忘了我的布谷鸟钟。
- No more clocks!
不要再有钟了！
- [moans]
（呻吟声）
- Fine! The outlet is over there!
好吧！插座在那边！
- [squeals]
（尖叫声）
- Ugghhh!
呃！
- Just go fold it! - [squeaks]
去把它折起来！（吱吱声）
- Click-click...
咔嚓-咔嚓...
- Fold, fold.
折叠，折叠。
- We are never going to win the gold.
我们永远也赢不了金牌。
- Nicky's gone.
尼基走了。
Finally, some peace and quiet.
终于，有些宁静了。
I need my brain sleep.
我需要让脑子休息一下。
Entry velocity doesn't calculate itself.
入弯速度不会自己计算。
Good night.
晚安。
- Good night.
Ricky?
瑞奇？
Why do you think they call it a bobsled?
为什么你觉得他们叫它bobsled？
- I have no idea. Good night.
我不知道。晚安。
- Ricky?
Ricky？
Why don't they call it a Jeff-sled
为什么不叫它Jeff-sled
or a Benjamin-sled?
或者Benjamin-sled？
- I don't know! Good night!
我不知道！晚安！
- Ricky? - What's with the questions?!
Ricky？这是怎么回事？！
- Can't sleep.
睡不着。
- Well, try counting sheep.
那就试着数羊吧。
- One sheep.
一只羊。
Two sheep... - To yourself.
两只羊...
- One sheep, Dicky.
- 一只羊，迪基。
Two sheep, Dicky.
- 两只羊，迪基。
- [muffled shouting] I miss Nicky!
- [模糊的喊声] 我想念尼基！
- I almost got it.
- 我差点就睡着了。
Oh, no, no. Oh, no, no--no!
哦，不，不。哦，不，不——不！
Ugh! [thud]
呃！[砰]
Found the other one!
找到另一只了！
- [loud snoring]
- [响亮的鼾声]
Is what I would sound like if I were really asleep.
如果我真的睡着了，我就会这样打呼噜。
- [whack] - What was that?
- [whack] - 那是什么？
- [calmly] Just thinking about something.
- [calmly] 只是在想些事情。
- Are you guys asleep?
- 你们睡着了吗？
- [snores]
No. But doesn't it sound like it?
没有。但听起来不像吗？
- [whack]
- No. It sounds like you guys are goofing off in here
- 不。听起来你们在这里偷懒
and not taking this race seriously.
而不是认真对待这场比赛。
We are gonna lose to those Kramdens
我们会输给那些克拉姆登的
and let Mom and Dad down.
让爸爸妈妈失望。
- How dare you walk in here with these accusations!
你怎么敢带着这些指控走进来！
Is what I would sound like if I were Ricky.
如果我是Ricky，我听起来会是这样。
- Well, excuse me... [whack]
好吧，原谅我... [whack]
if I care... [whack]
如果我在乎... [whack]
about winning! [whack]
赢的话！[whack]
- What does go on in here?
这里到底发生了什么？
[alarm ringing]
[警报响]
- Hey, not the face!
嘿，别打脸！
- Who are you? - You gettin' up
你是谁？ - 你是不是要起来
for your stupid race or not?
参加你那愚蠢的比赛？
Well, I'm not sure why it matters.
嗯，我不确定这有什么重要的。
You're just gonna panic, pull the brake,
你只会恐慌，拉刹车，
and let your whole family down again anyway.
然后再次让你的整个家庭失望。
- I am not! - Come on!
我不是！
All the clicky-clicky and windy-windy you keep doing?
来吧！
You know you're nervous.
你一直做的那些咔嗒咔嗒和呼呼声？
- I am not!
你知道你很紧张。
- Methinks you doth reset too much.
我不是！
- I'm not listening to you. You're just a dumb alarm clock.
我觉得你重置得太多了。
- Oh. You listen to me when I do this to wake you up...
我不听你的。你只是个愚蠢的闹钟。
[ringing]
[响铃]
But you won't listen to me when I tell you you're scared.
但当我告诉你你害怕时，你却不听我的。
- 'Cause I'm not!
- 因为我没有！
- You know I'm right...
- 你知道我是对的...
Nicky.
尼基。
- Nicky...Nicky?
- 尼基...尼基？
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
- Uh...no, I--
- 呃...不，我--
No. I-I can't do the race, Mae.
不，我不能参加比赛了，梅。
I'm gonna have to ask you to--
我得请你...
[Velcro rips]
[魔术贴撕开声]
- Please tell me you're gonna say, "Fill in for me."
- 请告诉我你会说，“替我上场。”
- Yes! - Oh, good.
- 是的！ - 哦，太好了。
'Cause I don't wanna have to reload this thing.
因为我不想重新装填这东西。
- ♪ La la la la la la la la-la ♪
- 感谢你为我做这件事，Mae。
- Thank you for doing this for me, Mae.
你真的是我们的第五位队员。
You really are the fifth quad.
我为你挺身而出感到骄傲。
I'm proud of you for stepping up.
- 我也为你感到骄傲。这需要很大的勇气
- And I'm proud of you. It takes a lot of guts
去告诉Dawn和男孩们你退出比赛。
to tell Dawn and the boys you're backing out of the race.
告诉Dawn和男孩们你退出比赛。
- [chuckles] Yeah. It does take a lotta guts.
- [轻笑]是的，这确实需要很大的勇气。
Which is why I'm gonna do this instead.
这就是为什么我要这么做。
Ow! Ah! Oh, my bobsledding ankle!
哎哟！啊！我的雪橇脚踝！
I think it's broken! Ah!
我觉得它断了！啊！
- No one's buying that.
- 没人会相信的。
- You're right, I...
- 你说得对，我...
I need some ice and an ankle wrap
我需要一些冰和脚踝包扎
to make it look better.
让它看起来更真实。
Thanks, Mae.
谢谢你，Mae。
[softly] Eee!
[轻声]哎呀！
- [shrilly] Eee!
- [尖锐]哎呀！
- What are you doing?
- 你在做什么？
- Can't sleep.
- 睡不着。
Was gonna try the couch.
我打算试试沙发。
- Can't sleep either.
- 我也睡不着。
Was going to try the couch,
我本来也打算试试沙发，
but now I'll try the bean bag.
但现在我打算试试懒人沙发。
- Good luck to you, sir.
- 祝你好运，先生。
- And you as well, sir.
- 也祝你好运，先生。
- Oh, good, you're awake.
哦，太好了，你醒着。
I can't take the pressure anymore.
我再也受不了这种压力了。
I know I'm gonna screw the calculations up again
我知道我会再次搞砸计算，
and lose the race, so I'm going to do this.
输掉比赛，所以我打算这么做。
Ow! My bobsledding neck!
哎哟！我的雪橇脖子！
You're going to have to take my place.
你得代替我的位置。
- Uh, Ricky, there might be a problem with that.
呃，里基，这可能有点问题。
- You're right--I'm going to need Dad's neck brace
你说得对——我需要爸爸的颈托
to really sell it. Thanks, Mae!
才能真正做到位。谢谢你，梅！
- Ugh.
呃。
- What are you doing?
- 你在干什么？
- Can't sleep.
- 睡不着。
- Me neither.
- 我也是。
- Good luck to you, sir.
- 祝你好运，先生。
- Whatever, dude.
- 随便吧，伙计。
Ow!
哎哟！
- What's the matter?
- 怎么了？
- I haven't decided yet.
- 我还没决定。
But it really hurts, and I need you to fill in for me.
但真的很疼，我需要你替我一下。
Thanks, Mae!
谢谢，梅！
- Ow! - Ow!
哎哟！
- Ow! - Ow...
哎哟！...
- Ow... - Owie...
哎哟......
- Hello.
哎呀。
- I could say the same to you.
我也可以这么说。
- Thought you were sleepin' on the couch.
以为你在沙发上睡呢。
- Fell off.
掉下来了。
Broke my bobsledding ankle.
弄伤了我的雪橇脚踝。
Thought you were, uh, crashing on the bean bag.
还以为你在豆袋椅上过夜呢。
- Crashed too hard. Wrenched my bobsledding neck.
摔得太狠了，扭到了我的雪橇脖子。
- Mae's filling in for me! - Mae's filling in for me!
- 梅在替我顶班！ - 梅在替我顶班！
- Oh, no, I'm sleep-walking next to this open window!
- 哦，不，我在开着的窗户旁边梦游！
[crash]
[撞击声]
Ah! [spits] Puh!
啊！[吐口水] 噗！
My bobsledding face!
我的雪橇脸！
- Oh, good, you're awake. You always have my back, right?
- 哦，太好了，你醒了。你总是支持我，对吧？
- Of course. - Awesome.
- 当然。 - 太棒了。
Thanks, Mae. Get some sleep.
谢谢，梅。去睡会儿吧。
- Ankle is much worse! - Please!
- 脚踝严重多了！ - 拜托！
A neck injury is a career-ender!
颈部受伤可是职业生涯终结者！
- My face!
- 我的脸！
[thudding]
[砰砰声]
- Hey, fellas. Ha.
- 嘿，伙计们。哈。
Yeah. I don't really think I can make the race today.
是啊。我真的觉得我今天参加不了比赛了。
I think I might have broken my bobsledding body.
我觉得我可能摔坏了我的雪橇身体。
What's up with you?
你怎么了？
- Uh...ankle! - Neck.
- 哎呀…脚踝！- 脖子。
- Face! - Ow!
- 脸！- 哎哟！
all: Mae's filling in for me!
全部人：梅替我上场！
- No, I'm not.
- 不，我没有。
Do any of you have any self-respect?
你们中有谁还有自尊心吗？
- What are you implying, Mae?
- 你这是什么意思，Mae？
- Look at yourselves...
- 看看你们自己...
faking injuries to get out of the race?
假装受伤来逃避比赛？
What are you all afraid of?
你们到底在害怕什么？
A little competition, losing?
一点点竞争，输掉比赛？
- Yeah. Both of those things.
- 是的，这两样都是。
- Nicky, Dicky, and I have blown it once already.
- Nicky, Dicky, 和我已经搞砸过一次了。
- And it's my turn to blow it this year.
- 今年轮到我搞砸了。
Which is why I was so freaked out.
这就是为什么我那么紧张。
It's just too much pressure.
只是压力太大了。
- You were a well-oiled machine
- 你曾经是一个运转良好的机器，
until those Kramdens entered the race
直到克拉姆登家的人加入了比赛，
and your dad said "no pressure."
你爸爸还说“没有压力”。
Now the only race you're trying to win
现在你唯一想赢的比赛
is to be the first to get me to replace you.
就是第一个让我替代你。
- I believe I won that race.
- 我相信我已经赢了那场比赛。
- I always wanted to be the fifth quad,
- 我一直想成为第五个四分卫，
and none of you even wants to be one through four.
而你们甚至没有人想成为第一到第四个。
- [sighs] Mae's right.
- [叹气] 梅是对的。
I mean, look at us.
我是说，看看我们。
We were all so afraid of being the one to let the others down
我们都害怕成为那个让其他人失望的人
that we already did.
结果我们已经做到了。
- Win or lose...
- 无论是赢是输...
[Velcro rips]
[魔术贴撕开声]
we do this together.
我们是一起做这件事的。
- So no offense, Mae, but we don't need you.
- 所以，Mae，无意冒犯，但我们不需要你。
- For the record, you needed me to point it out.
- 说句公道话，你们需要我指出来。
- True. Thanks, Mae.
- 没错。谢谢你，Mae。
All right. Now, let's get that good night's sleep,
好了。现在，让我们好好睡一觉，
stay together on those turns,
转弯时保持在一起，
and beat those Kramdens! - Yeah.
打败那些克拉姆登斯！- 是的。
- Hands in!
- 手放进来！
Come on, fifth quad, hand in.
来吧，第五组，把手放进来。
- Really? all: Really.
- 真的吗？大家：真的。
- Go, Harpers!
- 加油，哈珀家！
- All right, everyone to bed.
- 好了，大家都去睡觉。
[alarm rings, alarm buzzes, cuckoo clock chiming]
[闹钟响，闹钟嗡嗡响，布谷鸟钟报时]
[all moan] - All right, everybody wake up!
[大家都呻吟] - 好了，大家都醒醒！
- Who knows.
- 谁知道。
Maybe the Kramdens will oversleep.
也许克拉门一家会睡过头。
all: Let's go beat the Harpers.
大家：我们快去超过哈珀家。
- All right, everyone, we're leaving in ten minutes.
好的，各位，我们十分钟后出发。
I'm gonna need at least two of you to help me wake your mother.
我至少需要两个人帮我叫醒你们妈妈。
- [snoring]
（打呼声）
♪ ♪
- Oh, the Kramdens' time is gonna be tough to beat.
哦，克拉门家的时间很难超越。
- But it looks like Dawn and the boys are doing great!
但看起来道恩和孩子们做得很好！
- Well, it looks like they're really staying together
嗯，看起来他们在转弯时真的保持在一起。
on the turns.
在转弯时。
Tom, I think the kids are...
汤姆，我觉得孩子们...
asleep!
睡着了！
What?
什么？
Hey, hey--and so is Mae!
嘿，嘿——梅也睡着了！
Tom! - Sit up straight!
汤姆！ - 坐直了！
Show the logo!
展示标志！
- The Harper Quads are nearing the finish...
- 哈珀四胞胎即将到达终点...
and the Harpers win it in record time!
- 哈珀家以创纪录的时间获胜！
- No one can see the logo--
- 没人能看到标志——
And yay!
太棒了！
- I can't believe it.
我不敢相信。
They actually beat us in their sleep.
他们居然在睡梦中打败了我们。
- Come on, guys, get up!
快点，伙计们，起来！
This is your chance to rub it in their
这是你们向他们
adorable little faces.
可爱的小脸炫耀的机会。
- [loud snore]
（大声打鼾）
- As a fifth quad, I just wanna say
作为第五个四胞胎，我只想说
Go, Harpers!
加油，哈珀家！
♪ They won, they beat ya ♪
♪ 他们赢了，他们打败了你 ♪
♪ They sleeping, but they beat ya ♪
♪ 他们在睡觉，但他们打败了你 ♪
♪ They won, they beat you ♪
♪ 他们赢了，他们打败了你 ♪
♪ They sleepin', but they beat you ♪
♪ 他们睡着了，但他们打败了你 ♪
♪ They won, they beat you ♪
♪ 他们赢了，他们打败了你 ♪
♪ They sleepin', but they beat you, mmm ♪
♪ 他们睡着了，但他们打败了你，嗯 ♪
♪ They won, they beat you ♪
♪ 他们赢了，他们打败了你 ♪
♪ They sleepin', but they-- ♪
♪ 他们睡着了，但他们—— ♪
Beat you. They beat you.
打败了你。他们打败了你。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 是的，是的，是的，是的，是的 ♪
♪ 是的，是的，是的，是的 ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 是的！ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 是的，是的，是的，是的，是的 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 是的，是的，是的，是的 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 是的！ ♪